<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Scriptom</title>
    <author email="dev@groovy.codehaus.org">Jason Smith</author>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Scriptom">
      <p>
		<b>Scriptom</b> is an optional Groovy module originally developed by <a href="http://glaforge.free.fr/weblog">Guillaume Laforge</a>
		and currently maintained by Jason Smith. 
		It combines the elegant "syntactical sugar" of Groovy with the power of the 
		<a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/jacob-project/">Jacob library (<b>Ja</b>va <b>CO</b>M <b>B</b>ridge)</a>. 
		<b>Scriptom</b> lets you use <b>ActiveX</b> or <b>COM</b> Windows components from Groovy. The result is something that looks eerily 
		similar to <i>VBScript</i> - only groovier.
	  </p>

	  <p>
        You can use <b>Scriptom</b> to automate <b>Word</b> or <b>Excel</b> documents, control <b>Internet Explorer</b>, make your PC talk 
		using the <b>Microsoft Speech API</b>, monitor processes with <b>WMI</b> (Windows Management Instrumentation), or browse the 
		<b>Windows Registry</b> using <b>WShell</b> - and much more. <b>Scriptom</b> also provides an easy way to talk to custom 
		<b>VB6</b> or <b>Microsoft.NET</b> libraries.
	  </p>
	  
	  <p>
		Needless to say, <b>Scriptom</b> can be used only on Microsoft Windows.
	  </p>

	  <p>
	    <b>Scriptom</b> is included as an option in the <a href="http://groovy.codehaus.org/Download">Groovy Windows Installer</a>, 
		and <b>Scriptom</b> can be downloaded from <a href="./download.html">this website</a>. The <b>Scriptom</b> codebase is stable 
		and feature-complete. The <b>Jacob</b> project - <b>Scriptom</b>'s foundation - was started in 1999 and is being used in 
		countless production Java applications worldwide. <b>Scriptom</b> is now in wide use as well, and has proven to be stable and mature.
	  </p>

	  <p>
		<b>Scriptom</b> gives you all the <b>COM</b>-scripting power of <b>Jacob</b>, and it is a lot easier. 
	  </p>
	</section>
  </body>
</document>
